So in this lecture, we're going to look at fine tuning approaches.
So we're going to look at the how part, how is it done? Previously, we had tried to answer the
question of what, what is the outcome that we're going to generate? And here, we're going to talk
about the how part, how is it done? And from the exam perspective, you just need to
at a high level know what is the lower technique. Okay, now fine tuning approaches.
So there are two fine tuning approaches at a broad level. First is the full fine tuning.
So the full fine tuning updates all the model parameters across every transformation layer.
See, you can see here, you have the pre-terrain model and in full fine tuning,
you're going to update all the model weights and parameters.
So you get better results, but it requires very high compute and large memory.
So that's why it's used in very few circumstances. Next, we have something known as
PEFT parameter efficient fine tuning. So it freezes the base model weights and trains only
a small set of added parameters. So this is one of the approaches from parameter efficient fine
tuning, where you freeze the base model weights and you only add a small set of added parameters.
So this reduces the training cost while preserving the models pre-terrain knowledge. So that's
why it's a more common approach. So within parameter efficient fine tuning, there are different
ways in which you can achieve this. So one of them is Laura adapters prefix prompt tuning and
Q Laura. And from the exam perspective, you need to only focus on Laura. So now let's go ahead and
take a look. What is Laura? So Laura also called as lower rank adaptation. So AWS gives
two key use cases where you can use Laura. So domain adaptation for enterprise apps.
So healthcare provider might use Laura to adapt a base model to medical terminology and clinical
documentation standards. Again, our use case, let's say we are building a generative application
for physician summarization notes and our base model doesn't do a great job. There we can use
Laura to improve its domain knowledge. Then you have multi language adaptation. Let's say you
are a global e-commerce platform might employ Laura to adapt to their customer service model to
differentiate to different regional languages and cultural context. So these are the two use cases
that AWS highlights for lower rank adaptation. So just from the exam perspective, remember you're
going to use lower rank adaptation or Laura technique for fine tuning because it improves the model
performance, but keeps the training cost low and preserves the model's pre-read knowledge.
Okay, so that's pretty much it from this lecture. I'll see you in the next lecture. Thank you.